Okay, good!
Special Officers' School
Tactical Practice Grounds
Now further back!
Push them back!
Roger!
Do we go around?
Just wait, you pieces of scrap.
I'm gonna blow a giant hole
in your ass!
Hey, Marcel!
We're going to crash into it!
We're saved...
Ow...
Sorry, Eugene.
You okay?
I think so...
What the hell are you doing?!
Get out of there, now!
Cadet Marcel, what the hell was that?
February 11th, Stellar Year 2149
I wanted to get behind the enemy.
And so you went over the hill?
Exposing your Feldreß's belly
to enemy fire?
Your grade for this exercise is zero!
Go back to basic!
Yes, sir.
Next, Cadet Nouzen!
Jumping in a Vánagandr?
Are you insane?
Are you trying to destroy it?
I judged that it was the only way
to avoid a collision.
It's better to lose the legs on one
than losing both altogether.
Shin...
True.
I'll give you credit
for avoiding a collision.
But you still engaged in dangerous piloting.
So you get a zero, too.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
Nouzen!
I'm not gonna thank you!
I don't need you to.
For one thing, you didn't need to dodge.
I could've—
I said you don't need to.
Let's go, Eugene.
Come with me!
It's nice being young, isn't it?
Is that how it looks to you?
You're so cold.
What is it today?
I want you to come with me again.
I got permission.
Eugene, you need to put some distance
between you and Nouzen.
Why?
You know about the new Feldreß those
Eighty-Six are working on with R & D.
Those things are insane.
They're based on the Republic's designs,
which don't factor in pilot safety at all!
They say a dozen of its test pilots
have already died.
But none of them got hurt at all!
That's just a rumor.
Yeah...
But he gives me a bad feeling.
Almost as if...
As if what?
He's the Reaper.
Are you guys ready for a trip?
April 1st, Stellar Year 2149
How far are we going?
Is this a training exercise?
No idea.
But something's on those trucks, right?
Oh, with the tarp over it?
When you came through this place,
it was still under Legion control.
But we've taken this place back
over the last six months.
We moved up the battle lines
and found these stranded Republic Feldreß.
There was a plate among them
with names on it.
In the Federacy,
when someone dies in battle,
their name is engraved on a memorial
in the National Cemetery.
We decided the names
of your comrades on the plate,
all 575 of them,
should be recorded here.
So we did this.
Don't worry.
After we recorded the names on the plate,
we returned it to its original spot.
What do you think?
Thank you for your concern.
But you've graduated the
Special Officers' School,
so now you're part
of the Giad Federacy's military.
And before long,
you'll be sent into battle.
You'll be working in the Nordlicht squadron,
which is under my command.
I am Lt. Colonel Grethe Wenzel,
commander of the 1028th Test Unit.
Glad to be working with you all.
Thank you.
Hey, you didn't need to throw us off!
Frederica?
What is that?
Don't look!
This is a surprise!
A surprise?
That's right!
What is that?
A scavenger?
That's Republic tech.
Why?
Fido?
What are you saying, Shin?
Do you name all your pets
the same thing?
No, this is Fido.
The one who was with you.
We investigated when we found it
and discovered its core unit was intact.
Grethe rebuilt it.
We've replaced the mechanical parts,
but this is the real Fido!
It looks the same,
but it's several times stronger.
No way.
He also thought he was dead
and refused to activate at first.
He only turned on
when I gave him Shinei's name.
You are the proof that we made it here.
Perform your mission until you rust away.
You're still alive?
I ordered to do your mission
until you rusted away.
But well...
Want to go home together, once more?
Saw that coming.
Shouldn't you be a little worried?
That's right!
It'd take more than that to break Fido.
I meant Shinei!
Right!
Oh, he'll be fine.
Shin knows how Fido moves.
Really?
So he does know how to smile, huh?
So, Frederica, why are you here?
Because I'm your mascot.
"Mascot"?
You didn't know?
They have young girls like me
join a unit and eat and sleep with them.
The unit becomes a found family
and becomes willing to risk their lives
for their beloved daughter or sister.
It's a Giad tradition.
That's sickening.
Do you mean...
Yup.
I'll be joining the 1028th Test Unit.
Which means I'm your goddess of victory!
Why are you laughing?
By the way, Shinei.
I have another surprise for you.
I got it from Ernst.
It's important to you, isn't it?
Yeah.
Welcome back.
Welcome back!
Glad to be here.
July 28th, Stellar Year 2149
Giad Federacy Western Front Lines
Enemy squadron incoming!
Forty-five seconds to contact!
I'm not dying yet!
Damn it!
Where's our suppression fire?
Damn it all!
I'm not letting you
take me with you!
How many of these damn things are there?
Stand fast!
Even if you run, they'll catch you!
I'm honored to die
for my homeland and my comrades!
No!
That's the new Reginleif...
The Eighty-Six...
Monsters of the Republic!
Lieutenant, you used
the high-frequency blade again, didn't you?
Yes.
Stop abusing that thing!
We don't have a spare blade yet.
And even besides that,
the way you use it—
It's fine.
The Legion are going to withdraw.
Huh?
Roger.
Well done, Shinei!
You snuck in here again?
You can't get rid of me
by begging the repair crew to help you.
I told you not to follow us
onto the battlefield.
You're just a mascot.
Remember that.
You don't get to tell me that!
A commanding officer isn't supposed
to go running alone into enemy territory!
It's a bad habit!
Bernholdt was complaining.
Are you listening, Shinei?
You need to take care of yourself.
I can't get it off!
Help me, Bernholdt!
Right, right.
But you should quiet down.
Everybody's tired after days of fighting.
Yeah. Sorry...
Hey, what are Nordlicht doing here?
Giad Federacy Forward Operation Base 15 (FOB15)
We sent a request
for help yesterday, right?
A 2nd Lieutenant running a whole battalion?
Supposedly all his superior officers died.
Right now, it's at a squadron's staffing level.
Who killed them, I wonder?
The headless skeleton,
possessed by a Reaper.
Creepy.
Stop it, Eugene.
Sorry, you eat with the others.
Can I sit here?
Sure...
Eugene? You ended up here?
I got here last month.
It's good to see you again, Shin.
Yeah.
If you can't eat them,
don't force yourself.
But that would be rude to the kitchen staff.
Then try harder.
You saved us yesterday.
Oh, sorry.
There were so many requests
for help, I didn't notice.
You're busy, huh?
Busy enough for the squadron
to be split up.
That's why it's just the two of you.
Hey, I remember you!
You remembered me!
Of course!
I heard you ended up
in Shinei's class at school!
It must've been hard.
Yeah. He's really cold,
and he never talks.
You never know what he's thinking.
I know! I know!
You talk to him, and he doesn't even look up
from his book, or say a word!
If it's not something he's interested in,
he won't even listen!
And he does really crazy stuff at weird times!
That's right! That's right!
I think we'll get along.
Let's be friends!
Yes!
It's a pleasure to meet you!
Now!
How about we take a photo
to remember this day!
Yeah.
Shinei!
Is this part of the job
for a goddess of victory?
It's all I can do.
Now...
I don't want to interrupt a meeting
between old friends, so I'll be going!
She became a mascot, huh?
Yeah.
Nobody even likes that old custom anymore.
Even someone like her,
if she's there, we have to protect her.
We're all strangers,
so they must think they need a hostage.
That's awful.
She choose that path.
But she doesn't have a reason to fight, right?
Family, country, justice, making a living...
None of that matters to a kid that age!
So why does she have to fight?
You may be right.
How's your sister? Is she doing well?
Yeah, I think.
She's kind of lonely,
'cause she's staying with my aunt.
Aunt?
Oh, we don't have parents.
I want her to go to a good school,
so I need to make money.
It's rough being a big brother.
Great, isn't she?
You can't have her.
I've already got a little brat.
I'm taking her somewhere
on my next leave.
A zoo or an amusement park.
Maybe shopping. Since she's a little girl,
I bet she'd love clothes or shoes.
Then you really shouldn't have
joined the military, right?
The war's not going well.
And I don't think that's going to change.
Yes. My unit lost fifteen
people just yesterday.
Our commander said this is normal
when things get bad.
"Normal," huh?
I don't think that many dead is "normal."
The number of dead and the number
of destroyed Legion don't match at all.
It sure doesn't feel like we're winning.
From the generals' perspective,
it probably just means fewer mouths to feed.
Sorry!
No...
But then what about you?
Why did you...
Again? They never give up.
I bet girls don't like them.
Okay, see you later.
You're safe, right, Shinei?
Yeah.
Good.
But...
I'm sorry.
I have bad news.
Frederica, close your "eyes."
Nina...
The picture...
Nina's...
Please...
Thank you.
Eugene...
Did you do that, Nouzen?
Good timing.
Make the casualty report.
Why didn't you save him?
You could've done it!
You were too busy fighting
those hunks of steel, weren't you?
You battle-mad Eighty-Six!
Stop it, Lieutenant Marcel.
Are you no different
from those scum in the Republic?
I apologize.
And thank you for what
you did for Lieutenant Rantz.
No...
So let me say this.
If you joined up out of a desire
to repay us for saving you, there's no need.
We will never force poor children
like you to fight.
It's not too late.
Leave the army and live happily.
The Legion are coming.
Meet up with your allies while you can.
Shinei?
What's the situation?
Not good.
Nordlicht has new orders.
Gather up at point 27-32
in preparation for a new attack.
Then stand by for further orders.
Roger.
Shinei.
You're okay, right?
Yeah.
"Welcome back."